Fernando Alvarez

San Bartolomé, Canary Islands, Spain



feralvarz@gmail.com



0034630974741



linkedin.com/in/alvarezfer

Summary

Senior Frontend Developer with +14 years of experience. Always looking for clean, efficient, and functional code by employing the best design along with excellent knowledge of the latest best practices.

Experienced in Angular, RxJS, NgRx, HTML5, CSS3, Responsive Web Development, and modern Javascript.

Experience

Senior Frontend Developer

Mosaic.tech

Sep 2019 - Dec 2020 (1 year 4 months)

Worked along with the front-end team to build a stable version for a Fintech tool.

- Built user interfaces, components library with scalability in mind.
- Worked with Angular 10, Angular Material, and Stencil components.
- Improved app performance by using NgRx and RxJS.
- Web Application development from alpha to v1.0, currently being used by customers.

Senior Frontend Developer

South Geeks

Sep 2019 - Dec 2020 (1 year 4 months)

Web Designer / Developer

Centric Digital

Jul 2012 - Aug 2019 (7 years 2 months)

Centric Digital provides solutions to measure and raise digital intelligence. Assists traditional business to understand online trends and how they can remain ahead of the competition in the age of digital disruption.

- Working remotely since 2012
- Ux Design, quick prototyping using Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator.
- Web development for a variety of clients from musicians, startups to larger companies.
- Knowledge of web ecosystem and best practices.
- Implementation of large sets of data in D3 charts, from custom API.
- Technologies: Html5, Css3, Javascript, Typescript, Angular 6, Angular Material, Angular CLI, Bootstrap 4, D3, Sass, Less, Wordpress, Shopify, GIT, JIRA, SourceTree, ESLint

Frontend Developer / Ux Designer

Freelance

Jan 2008 - Mar 2013 (5 years 3 months)

As freelance, in this period I gained experience in web development. I had a variety of roles like Ux Designer and Web Developer for small and mid size clients. Most of this pages doesn't exist or haven been redesigned due the age of projects.

- Website design, sites, banners, content pieces.
- Web development, custom Wordpress themes, web maintenance and bug fixing.
- Technologies: Html5, Css3, Sass, Less, Wordpress, Gulp, Photoshop, Illustrator.

Education



Diseñador Gráfico | Graphic Designer 2006 - 2009 Licenciatura cursada completa.

Licenses & Certifications

- in Node.js Essential Training LinkedIn
- in React: Ecosystems LinkedIn
- React Native Ecosystem and Workflow LinkedIn
- React Course Codecademy
- React.js: Part II Course Codecademy
- in Learning Gatsby LinkedIn

Skills

AngularJS • Front-end Development • Javascript • Web Development • User Experience • Unit Testing • SASS • HTML 5 • React.js • Wordpress